Giselle Sanchez

Email: gisellesanchez@pursuit.org

https://github.com/gsanchez13 | http://www.linkedin.com/in/giselle-sanchez13 | https://gisellesanchez.co

SKILLS

Technical

ECMAScript 6, React, Node.js, Express.js, CSS3, HTML5, PostgreSQL, REST APIs, Postman, Git, GitHub, Data Structures & Algorithms, Redux, Code Review and Whiteboarding

PROJECTS

Ethic Attire

In alignment with the UN's sustainable fashion goals, this full stack web application aims to make an impact in the fashion industry by providing a simple clothing tracking system, education on materials, and resources for future purchases to consumers.

- Worked collaboratively with peers during a week-long Uber sponsored Hackathon event.
- Curated frontend that displays individual clothing items belonging to a user, developed with React libraries, and uses vanilla CSS to create a simple and appealing UI for better user experience.
- Created polished PostgreSQL gueries for specific data return in routes.

Marathoner

A full stack web app that is a social application that allows users to interact with one another based on television shows they are currently watching.

- Uses RESTful API requests with PostgreSQL queries to obtain information of programs.
- Formats client-friendly frontend with React components.

EXPERIENCE

Citi

Tampa, FL

Technology Analyst

July 2020 - Present

- Participated in a 4 week summer internship that focused on Data Analysis, Wrangling and Visualization, Cloud Engineering with AWS, UX safety and soundness and Developer best Practices.
- Part of the Data Transformation team under GFTS for EIOT, assisting in tasks relating to setting up a PoC for a new project, creating dashboards using PowerBI for solution testing, and creating schemas and documentation for proposed solutions.

NorthEast Community Bank

New York. NY

Customer Service Associate

June 2018 - June 2020

- Manage clientele's finances through extensive record keeping, active customer service and account alterations with use of MISER online banking software.
- Use a cross-departmental support system to resolve any consumer problems or inquiries on a daily basis, while also handling cash in terms of shipments, ATM and customer disbursements.
- Maintain a secure system by establishing relationships with patrons through functional communication and strict protocols, such as FDIC and BSA regulations.

Niketown

New York, NY

Part-time Athlete

Feb 2016 - July 2017

- Provided premium service to all consumers while relating to athletic knowledge through focused interactions and using company service ethos to fully create a positive experience for all consumers.
- Strived towards meeting store goals, such as higher conversion rates based on daily 2000+ foot traffic and a minimum of 2.5 units per transaction.

EDUCATION

Pursuit

Long Island City, NY June 2019 - June 2020

12-month Full Stack Web intensive coding program with a 9% acceptance rate.

Baruch College - Zicklin School of Business

New York, NY

Bachelor of Business Administration in International Business, Minors in Marketing and Spanish

Jan 2016 - May 2018